人人影视 原创翻译 双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译｜杏仁·Groot·斯嘉丽　银护·Groot·凉开水　PiPi·Groot·PiPi　草·Groot·草
校对｜银河护卫草　时间轴｜想念Gallifrey的Wholock　后期｜8T　总监｜somehacker　草草
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
[密苏里州]
[地球 密苏里州]
♫ 海港小镇有个姑娘 ♫
♪ There's a girl in this harbor town. ♪
♫ 她给人倒威士忌为生 ♫
♪ And she works layin' whiskey down. ♪
♫ 客人喊“布兰迪 再倒一圈” ♫
♪ They say, "Brandy, fetch another round". ♪
♫ 她给他们倒上各种美酒 ♫
♪ And she serves them whiskey and wine. ♪
♫ 水手都说“布兰迪 你是个好姑娘” ♫
♪ The sailors say "Brandy, you're a fine girl". ♪
♫ “你肯定会是个好妻子” ♫
♪ "What a good wife you would be." ♪
- 快来 快来  - 慢点
- Come on! Come on!  - Slow down!
这边 我的水百合 快来
This way, my river lily! Come on!
你要带我去哪
Where are you taking me?
快来快来
Come on, come on.
看啊 看
Look. Look!
好漂亮
Oh, it's beautiful!
我还担心它会不适应土壤
I was afraid it wouldn't take to the soil...
但它迅速扎了根
but it rooted quickly.
不久 它就会到处都是了
And soon, it'll be everywhere.
遍布宇宙
All across the universe.
我不知道你在说什么
Well, I don't know what you're talking about...
但我喜欢你说话的样子
but I like the way you say it.
我的心属于你
My heart is yours...
梅瑞狄斯·奎尔
Meredith Quill.
我不敢相信我爱上了一个太空人
I can't believe I fell in love with a spaceman.
[34年后]
[索维林星]
准备大展身手 混蛋们
Showtime, a-holes!
它随时会来
It will be here any minute.
那就是它倒霉了
Which will be its loss.
我以为你的武器是剑
I thought your thing was a sword?
我们受雇 阻止一个跨纬度怪物
We've been hired to stop an interdimensional beast
汲取这些电池的能量
from feeding on those batteries,
难道我还拿剑对付它
and I'm gonna stop it with a sword?
剑是你的武器 枪是我的专属嘛
It's just, swords were your thing and guns were mine.
但好吧 我们现在都用枪了
But I guess we're both doing guns now.
我之前不知道而已
I just didn't know that.
德拉克斯 你为什么没穿火箭的飞行装置
Drax, why aren't you wearing one of Rocket's aero-rigs?
穿上疼
It hurts.
It hurts?
我乳头很敏感
I have sensitive nipples.
“我乳头疼 我的天啊”
"My nipples hurt! Oh, goodness me!"
那他呢 他在干什么
What about him? What's he doing?
我在组装这个 这样就能边干活边听歌了
I'm finishing this so we can listen to tunes while we work.
这怎么重要了
How is that a priority?
怪奎尔啊 是他那么爱听歌
Blame Quill. He's the one who loves music so much.
不 其实我同意德拉克斯
No, I actually agree with Drax on this.
现在那个可不重要
That's hardly important right now.
好吧 好啊 奎尔
Okay. Sure, Quill.
不 认真的 我同意德拉克斯
No, seriously, I side with Drax.
我懂 你现在非常认真
No, I understand that. You're being very serious right now.
我能清楚看见你在眨眼
I can clearly see you winking.
该死 我眨的是左眼吗
Damn it. I'm using my left eye?
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
他们没斜眼看你
They were not looking at you funny.
要动真格的了
Well, that's intense.
银河护卫队2
格鲁特
Groot!
格鲁特 快闪开 你会受伤的
Groot, get out of the way! You're gonna get hurt!
不不 快吐出来
No! No! Spit it out!
快点
Come on!
真恶心
Disgusting!
这怪物的皮太厚了 从外面刺不穿
The beast's hide is too thick to be pierced from the outside.
必须从里面切穿它
I must cut through it from the inside.
不不 德拉克斯 等等
No, no! Drax, wait a minute!
德拉克斯
Drax!
他干什么
What is he doing?
他说皮太厚了
He said the skin is too thick
从外面刺不穿 所以他
to be pierced from the outside, so he...
- 这根本没道理  - 我想告诉他来着
- That doesn't make any sense!  - I tried telling him that!
它的皮不管内外
Skin is the same level of thickness
都一样厚
from the inside as from the outside!
我意识到了
I realize that.
它脖子上有个切口
There is a cut on its neck.
火箭 让它抬头
Rocket, get it to look up.
你个大海猴子 看上面
Hey, you giant Sea-Monkey! Up here!
小心 奎尔
Watch it, Quill!
太棒了 我一个人打败了这头怪物
Yes! I have single-handedly vanquished the beast!
怎么了
What?
它们叫什么来着
What are they called again?
能量电池
Anulax batteries.
棱酿电池
Harbulary batteries.
跟我说的完全不搭边
That's nothing like what I just said.
但它们每个都值几万块
But they're worth thousands of units apiece
所以索维林族雇我们保护它们
which is why the Sovereign hired us to protect them.
跟这些人打交道小心措辞 他们很容易生气
Careful what you say around these folks. They're easily offended.
冒犯了他们会被处死
The cost of transgression is death.
我们感谢你们拿生命冒险 银河护卫队
We thank you, Guardians, for putting your lives on the line.
我们不能让索维林子民去冒生命危险
We could not risk the lives of our own Sovereign citizens.
每个人都完全是按照族群的设计诞生的
Every citizen is born exactly as designed by the community.
身体和头脑都完美无缺
Impeccable, both physically and mentally.
我们控制后代的DNA
We control the DNA of our progeny...
让他们在生育荚里发育
germinating them in birthing pods.
我更喜欢用传统办法造人
I guess I prefer to make people the old-fashioned way.
也许哪天你可以给我讲讲历史
Perhaps someday, you could give me a history lesson...
讲讲我们祖先古老的方法
in the archaic ways of our ancestors.
为了学术研究
For academic purposes.
我很荣幸 好的
I would be honored, yes.
以学术研究的名义
In the name of research...
我觉得那会非常
I think that could be pretty...
非常令人反感
pretty repulsive.
我不喜欢随便…
I'm not into that kind of casual...
行了
Oh, please.
你们答应我们出力会有报酬的
Your people promised something in exchange for our services.
拿出来 我们马上就走
Bring it and we shall gladly be on our way.
家人团聚
Family reunion.
我知道她是你妹妹
I understand she is your sister.
她对我来说 只值山达尔的悬赏而已
She's worth no more to me than the bounty due for her on Xandar.
她想盗窃电池 被我们的士兵抓了个正着
Our soldiers apprehended her attempting to steal the batteries.
请随意处置她吧
Do with her as you please.
我们非常感谢您 阿耶莎大祭司
We thank you, High Priestess Ayesha.
你是什么出身 奎尔先生
What is your heritage, Mr. Quill?
我母亲来自地球
My mother is from Earth.
你父亲呢
And your father?
他不是密苏里人 我只知道这些
He ain't from Missouri. That's all I know.
我在你身上看到了
I see it within you.
一种不同寻常的血统
An unorthodox genealogy.
这种混血看起来特别…
A hybrid that seems particularly...
鲁莽
reckless.
你知道吗 我听说你们都是自以为是的混蛋
You know, they told me you people were conceited douchebags...
但那完全不是事实
but that isn't true at all.
糟糕
Oh, shit.
我又用错眼睛了 是吗
I'm using my wrong eye again, aren't I?
我很抱歉 我没想被你发现的
I'm sorry. That was meant to be behind your back.
他们没杀你算你走运
Count yourself blessed they didn't kill you.
还用你说
You're telling me.
你想买点电池吗
You wanna buy some batteries?
好吧 我们把小秃子送去山达尔领赏吧
All right, let's get baldy to Xandar and collect that bounty.
[劲歌金曲 第二辑]
她说我父亲的那些话
That stuff about my father...
她以为她是谁啊
Who does she think she is?
我知道你对那件事有点敏感
I know you're sensitive about that.
我才没有敏感 我只是不知道他是什么人
I'm not sensitive about it. I just don't know who he is.
如果我看起来像是在跟大祭司调情那很抱歉
Sorry if it seemed like I was flirting with the High Priestess.
我没那个意思
I wasn't.
即使你有我也不在意
I don't care if you were.
我觉得你在意
Well, I feel like you do care.
所以我在道歉 对不起
That's why I'm apologizing. So, sorry!
卡魔拉不适合你 奎尔
Gamora is not the one for you, Quill.
鬼鬼祟祟的
Damn shadow.
宇宙中有两种人
There are two types of beings in the universe...
一种是跳舞的人 另一种是不跳舞的人
those who dance, and those who do not.
我第一次见到我的爱人是在一场战争集会上
I first met my beloved at a war rally.
天哪
Oh, God.
村子里每个人都在跳舞
Everyone in the village flailed about, dancing.
除了一个女人
Except one woman.
我的奥薇特
My Ovette.
我立刻就知道她是我的真命天女
I knew immediately she was the one for me.
即使听着最有旋律的音乐
The most melodic song in the world could be playing.
她连脚都不会点一下
She wouldn't even tap her foot.
动都不会动一下
Wouldn't move a muscle.
看上去就像是死了
One might assume she was dead.
听起来很性感
That does sound pretty hot.
我下面都要充血了
It would make my nether regions engorge.
好吧 我懂了 没错
Okay. I get it, yes.
我是个舞者 而卡魔拉不是
I'm a dancer, Gamora is not.
你只需要找到一个跟你一样不着调的女人
You just need to find a woman who is pathetic... like you.
我饿了 那些亚罗根给我来点
I'm hungry. Hand me some of that yaro root.
不行 还没熟
No. It's not ripe yet...
而且我恨你
and I hate you.
你恨我
You hate me?
你丢下了我 自己去偷那块石头了
You left me there while you stole that stone for yourself.
而现在你却像个英雄一样
And yet here you stand, a hero.
很快我就能摆脱这枷锁
I will be free of these shackles soon enough,
然后我会杀了你
and I will kill you.
我发誓
I swear.
不
No.
你会在山达尔的监狱里
You're gonna live out the rest of your days
度过余生
in a prison on Xandar...
做那个白日梦
wishing you could.
奇怪
This is weird.
有一队索维林飞船从后面追上来了
We've got a Sovereign fleet approaching from the rear.
他们为什么要这样
Why would they do that?
可能是因为火箭偷了他们几个电池
Probably because Rocket stole some of their batteries.
老兄
Dude!
哦
Right.
他没偷电池
He didn't steal some of those.
我不知道他们为什么追我们 真奇怪啊
I don't know why they're after us. What a mystery this is.
你怎么想的
What were you thinking?
哥们 那些电池真的很容易偷
Dude, they were really easy to steal!
- 这就是你的辩解  - 拜托
- That's your defense?  - Come on!
你看到那个大祭司高高在上的样子了
You saw how that High Priestess talked down to us.
我这是在教训她
Now I'm teaching her a lesson!
我没想到你的动机这么无私
I didn't realize your motivation was altruism.
真是遗憾啊
It's really a shame
那些索维林人没领会到你的好意
the Sovereign have mistaken your intentions...
- 还想杀掉我们  - 说的太对了
- and they're trying to kill us.  - Exactly!
我是在讽刺你
I was being sarcastic!
不
Oh, no!
你应该用讽刺的语气 这下我出丑了
You're supposed to use a sarcastic voice! Now I look foolish!
斗嘴先省省好不好
Can we put the bickering on hold
活过这场太空大战再说
until after we survive this massive space battle?
- 更多敌人朝我们来了  - 很好
- More incoming!  - Good!
我想杀杀人
I wanna kill some guys!
你谁也没杀掉
You're not killing anyone.
这些飞船都是遥控驾驶的
All those ships are remotely piloted.
该死
Damn it!
在磨蹭什么 舰队司令
What is the delay, Admiral?
大祭司 那些电池
High Priestess, the batteries,
它们极其易燃
they are exceptionally combustible...
可能会摧毁整个舰队
and could destroy the entire fleet.
我们在意的是他们对我们的不敬
Our concern is their slight against our people.
我们雇佣了他们 他们却偷我们的
We hired them and they steal from us.
这是最大的亵渎
It is heresy of the highest order.
所有操作单位
All command modules...
对目标格杀勿论
fire with the intent to kill.
最近的宜居星球是哪里
What's the nearest habitable planet?
是一个叫博赫特的星球
It's called Berhert.
- 需要几次星际跳跃  - 只要一次
- How many jumps?  - Only one.
但进入点在四十七公里外
But the access point is 47 clicks away.
而且你得穿过那片量子小行星群
And you have to go through that quantum asteroid field.
奎尔 要想穿过那里
Quill, to make it through that
你得是全宇宙最棒的飞行员
you'd have to be the greatest pilot in the universe.
那我们走运了
Lucky for us,
- 我就…  - 我就是
- I...  - I am.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我从十岁就开始开这玩意了
I've been flying this rig since I was 10 years old.
我就是为开宇宙飞船而设计制造的
I was cybernetically engineered to pilot a spacecraft.
你就是设计制造成了个混蛋
You were cybernetically engineered to be a douchebag!
- 别闹了  - 奎尔
- Stop it.  - Quill.
今天晚上 你躺在床上的时候
Later on tonight, you're gonna be laying down in your bed
你的枕套里会有黏糊糊的一坨
and there's gonna be something squishy in your pillow case.
你会想“这是什么”
And you're gonna be like, "What's this?"
那会是我放的一坨屎
And it's gonna be because I put a turd in there!
你敢把你的屎放我床上 我就剃光你
You put your turd in my bed, I shave you.
才不会放我的
It won't be my turd.
我会放德拉克斯的
It will be Drax's.
我的屎蛋出了名的大
I have famously huge turds.
我们都快要死了 现在就讨论这个吗
We're about to die, and this is what we're discussing?
混蛋
Son of a...
哥们 搞什么
Dude! Seriously!
我来…
Let me...
蠢货
Idiots!
奎尔开飞船就这下场
Well, that's what you get when Quill flies.
还有一架索维林飞船在追我们
We still have a Sovereign craft behind us.
我们武器坏了
Our weapons are down.
还有二十公里跳跃
Twenty clicks to the jump!
坐稳了
Hold on.
还没熟呢
It's not ripe.
[应急宇航服 也可以穿着玩]
加油 扎莱克 你可以的
Come on, Zylak. You can do this.
太棒了
Yes!
还有十五公里跳跃
Fifteen clicks to the jump!
加油
Come on!
继续
Keep going!
还有十公里
Ten clicks!
去死吧 破船
Die, spaceship!
你弱爆了 扎莱克
You suck, Zylak.
不出所料
Typical.
还有五公里
Five clicks!
混蛋
Son of a...
他们绕过了星群
They went around the field!
有人摧毁了我们所有的飞船
Someone destroyed all our ships!
什么
What?
是谁
Who?
还有一公里
One click!
- 那是什么  - 管他呢
- What is that?  - Who cares?
跳跃点就在那儿 快 快
That's the jump point! Go! Go!
那是个人
It's a guy.
天啊
Oh, my God.
他还在外面吗
He's still out there?
格鲁特 系好安全带
Groot, put your seatbelt on!
准备好要强行降落了
Prepare for a really bad landing!
[博赫特星]
刚才太赞了
That was awesome!
棒
Yes!
你看看
Look at this!
咱们飞船的另一半呢
Where is the other half of our ship?
是我的船
My ship.
你们任何一个都可以带我们平安穿过星群
Either one of you could have gotten us through that field...
如果你们肯用上面这个
had you flown with what's between your ears
而不是下面那个驾驶飞船
instead of what's between your legs!
如果我下面那个长了手
If what's between my legs had a hand on it...
那我绝对可以用它来降落飞船
I guarantee I could have landed this ship with it.
彼得
Peter,
我们差点被你的傲慢害死
we almost died because of your arrogance.
是因为他偷能量电池还差不多
More like because he stole the Anulax batteries!
那个叫棱酿电池
They're called Harbulary batteries.
不 不叫那个
No, they're not!
你知道我为什么那么做吗 星嚼
Do you know why I did it, Star-Munch?
我才不叫“星嚼”
I'm not gonna answer to "Star-Munch."
因为我乐意
I did it because I wanted to!
混蛋
Dick.
我们为什么要讨论这个
What are we even talking about this for?
刚才有个小人炸了五十艘飞船救了我们
We just had a little man save us by blowing up 50 ships!
有多小
How little?
我也不知道 大概这么小
Well, I don't know, like this?
一个一英寸的小人救了我们吗
A little one-inch man saved us?
他要是近一点 肯定就会大一点吧
Well, if he got closer, I'm sure he would be much larger.
那叫近大远小 你个傻浣熊
That's how eyesight works, you stupid raccoon.
别叫我浣熊
Don't call me a raccoon!
抱歉 是我过分了
I'm sorry. I took it too far.
我是想说垃圾熊猫
I meant trash panda.
那样好听点吗
Is that better?
我不知道
I don't know.
这个更损 这个损多了
It's worse. It's so much worse.
你个混蛋
You son of a...
- 我受够你了  - 别过来
- I've had it with you!  - No! Back up!
有人从跳跃点跟着你们来了
Someone followed you through the jump point.
放了我 你们需要我帮忙
Set me free, you'll need my help.
我又不傻 星云
I'm not a fool, Nebula.
如果在战斗中拒绝帮助就是犯傻
You are a fool if you deprive yourself a hand in combat.
我一放了你 你就会攻击我的
You'll attack me the moment I let you go.
我不会的
No, I won't.
你这种超级大坏蛋不是应该很会说谎吗
You'd think an evil supervillain would learn how to properly lie.
我赌是那个一英寸的小人
I bet it's the one-inch man.
时隔这么多年 我终于找到你了
After all these years, I've found you.
你到底是谁
And who the hell are you?
我以为我沧桑帅气的外表就足以说明了
I figured my rugged good looks would make that obvious.
我叫伊戈
My name is Ego...
我是你爸爸 彼得
and I'm your dad, Peter.
[康特阿克夏星]
你知道俗话怎么说的
You know what they say...
“跟过鸭鸭 好运就来”
"You're out of luck until you've gone duck."
勇度
Yondu!
快下来
Come on down!
兜兜转转这么多年
After going around years in circles...
跟我最终娶的这女人周旋
with this woman I end up marrying.
我说 “艾丽塔 我爱你
I said, "Aleta, I love you, girl...
但你真是疯了”
"But you're losing your mind!"
话说回来 她一直都那样
Then again, she's always been that way.
我从来都不能相信她
I could never trust her. You know?
斯塔卡
Stakar.
好久不见
It's been some time.
看来这个场子
It seems like this establishment
堕落错了方式
is the wrong kind of disreputable.
- 先生  - 斯塔卡
- Sir!  - Stakar!
掠夺者有一百个派系
There's a hundred Ravager factions.
你为了接待其中一个 而失去了剩下九十九个的
You lost the business of 99 of them by serving one.
求你了 先生 别走
Please, sir. Please!
- 别碰我  - 求你
- Get away from me.  - Please!
你下地狱吧
You can go to hell then!
我不在乎你怎么看我
I don't give a damn what you think of me!
那你跟着我们干什么
So what are you following us for?
因为你必须听我说
Because you're gonna listen to what I gotta say!
我什么都不用听 是你背叛了准则
I don't gotta listen to nothing! You betrayed the code!
掠夺者不买卖孩子
Ravagers don't deal in kids.
我告诉过你 我不知道是怎么回事
I told you before! I didn't know what was going on!
你不知道
You didn't know
是因为你不想知道
because you didn't want to know
因为你靠这个发财
because it made you rich.
我要求有一席之地 我跟你们一样佩戴焰标
I demand a seat at the table! I wear these flames, same as you.
你虽然穿得像我们
You may dress like us...
但你死后别想听到自由号角声 勇度
but you'll never hear the Horns of Freedom when you die, Yondu.
奥戈尔的颜色
And the Colors of Ogord...
也绝不会在你的墓上闪耀
will never flash over your grave.
要是你觉得
If you think...
流放你 让我高兴
I take pleasure in exiling you...
那你就错了
you're wrong.
你伤了我们所有人的心
You broke all our hearts.
可悲
Pathetic.
起先 奎尔背叛了我们
First, Quill betrays us...
结果勇度把他毫发无伤地放走了
and Yondu just lets him go scot-free.
我们跟随他 是因为他
We followed him because he was the one
敢做不得不做的事
who wasn't afraid to do what needed to be done.
看来他变软弱了
Seems he's goin' soft.
要是他软弱 你这么小声干吗
If he's so soft, why are you whispering for?
你知道我说得对 克拉林
You know I'm right, Kraglin.
小心点 怎么说我们船长呢
You best be very careful what you say about our captain.
这是谁
Who the hell is that?
勇度·尤冬塔
Yondu Udonta...
我有个提议
I have a proposition for you.
你母亲去世后
I hired Yondu to pick you up
我雇了勇度去接你
when your mother passed away.
但他没有把你还给我
But instead of returning you...
而是把你留下了
Yondu kept you.
我不知道为什么
I have no clue as to why.
我告诉你为什么
Well, I'll tell you why.
因为我是个瘦得皮包骨的小孩
Because I was a skinny little kid
能溜进成年人进不去的地方
who could squeeze into places adults couldn't.
偷东西更容易
It made it easier for thievin'.
从那时起 我就一直在寻找你的下落
Well, I've been trying to track you down ever since.
我还以为勇度是你父亲
I thought Yondu was your father.
什么 我们在一起这么久
What? We've been together this whole time
你以为勇度是我的血亲
and you thought Yondu was my actual blood relative?
你俩长得一模一样
You look exactly alike.
勇度是蓝的
One's blue!
不 他不是我父亲
No, he's not my father!
勇度绑架了我
Yondu was the guy who abducted me
把我打得满地找牙 让我学会怎么打架
kicked the crap out of me so I could learn to fight
威胁要吃了我 让我一直担惊受怕
and kept me in terror by threatening to eat me.
- 吃了你  - 是啊
- Eat you?  - Yeah.
那个王八蛋
That son of a bitch.
你怎么找到我们的
How'd you locate us now?
哪怕像我住得那么偏僻
Even where I reside, out past the edge of what's known
也听说过传说中的星爵
we've heard tell about the man they call Star-Lord.
我们现在就出发去那儿怎么样
What say we head out there right now?
欢迎你的伙伴一起去
Your associates are welcome.
包括那只三角脸猴子
Even that triangle-faced monkey there.
我保证
I promise you...
那是一个与众不同的地方
it's unlike any other place you've ever seen.
在那里
And there...
我能给你解释你特别的身世
I can explain your very special heritage.
终于能做
Finally get to be the...
我一直想做的那个父亲了
father I've always wanted to be.
失陪了
Excuse me.
我去撒泡尿
I've gotta take a whiz.
我不信
I'm not buying it.
我们去散步吧
Let's go take a walk.
我叫螳螂
I am Mantis.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
微笑
Smiling.
我听说 这样做能让人们喜欢你
I hear it is the thing to do to make people like you.
你那么笑可不能
Not if you do it like that.
我一个人在伊戈的星球上长大
I was raised alone on Ego's planet.
我不了解人际交流的微妙
I do not understand the intricacies of social interaction.
我能摸摸你的狗狗吗 它好可爱
Can I pet your puppy? It is adorable.
可以
Yes.
这叫恶作剧
That is called a practical joke!
我很喜欢
I liked it very much!
是我刚想的
I just made it up!
饶了我吧
Give me a break!
都过了这么久了 突然出现
After all this time, you're gonna show up,
- 还突然要当我爸  - 是啊
- and just all of a sudden you wanna be my dad?  - I hear you.
另外 这可能是个陷阱 好吗
And by the way, this could be a trap. Okay?
克里纯种主义者 掠夺者
The Kree purists, the Ravagers...
- 都想杀死我们  - 我知道 但是…
- they all want us dead.  - I know, but...
但是什么
But what?
你给我讲的扎渡·霍索妇的故事呢
What was that story you told me about Zardu Hasselfrau?
谁
Who?
有一艘魔法船的那个
He owned a magic boat?
大卫·霍索夫
David Hasselhoff?
就是他
Right.
不是魔法船 是会说话的车
Not a magic boat. A talking car.
为什么会说话来着
Why did he talk again?
为了帮他打击犯罪 并给予精神支持
To help him fight crime, and to be supportive.
你小时候会随身带着他的照片
As a child, you would carry his picture in your pocket
告诉其他小孩
and you would tell all the other children
说他是你父亲 但他出门了
that he was your father, but that he was out of town.
拍摄《霹雳游侠》或者跟乐队在德国巡回演出
Shooting Knight Rider or touring with his band in Germany.
那是我喝醉时告诉你的
I told you that when I was drunk.
你现在提它干吗
Why are you bringing that up now?
我喜欢那个故事
I love that story.
我讨厌那个故事
I hate that story.
太可悲了
It's so sad!
我小时候总是看着其他孩子
As a kid, I used to see all the other kids off
跟他们的爸爸玩投接球
playing catch with their dad. And I
我也想让爸爸陪我玩 那是我最大的心愿
I wanted that, more than anything in the world!
我就想说这个 彼得
That's my point, Peter.
如果这个人就是你的霍索夫呢
What if this man is your Hasselhoff?
听着 如果我们发现他是坏人
Listen, if he ends up being evil...
那就杀了他
we will just kill him.
你要把我丢给那只狐狸
You're leaving me with that fox?
他不是狐狸
He's not a fox.
要是她行为可疑 就开枪打她
Shoot her if she does anything suspicious.
- 或者你想打就打  - 好
- Or if you feel like it.  - Okay.
就几天而已
It'll be just a couple of days.
还没等火箭修好飞船 我们就能回来了
We'll be back before Rocket's finished fixing the ship.
要是索维林人来了怎么办
What if the Sovereign come?
他们不可能知道我们在这儿 走吧
There's no way for them to know we're here. Let's go.
我觉得兵分两路不太好
I'm uncertain about parting ways.
天啊 你就像个老太婆
God, you're like an old woman.
因为我睿智吗
Because I'm wise?
你怎么有这么多行李
Why do you have so much luggage?
我不想让格鲁特乱动我的东西
I don't want Groot playing with my things.
希望老爸不像你那么混蛋 小孤儿
I hope Daddy isn't as big of a dick as you, orphan boy.
你的目的是什么 让所有人都讨厌你吗
What is your goal here? To get everybody to hate you?
你成功了
Because it's working.
我能问你个私人问题吗
Hey, can I ask you a personal question?
还没人问过我私人问题呢
No one has ever asked me a personal question.
你的触角是干什么的
Your antennae, what are they for?
触角的用途
Their purpose?
对 奎尔和我打了个赌
Yes. Quill and I have a bet.
哥们 你不应该说出来的
Dude. You're not supposed to say that!
我说
I say...
当你要穿过一个很低的门框时
that if you are about to go through a doorway that is too low...
你的触角能感知高度
your antennae will feel this,
防止你撞掉脑袋
and keep you from being decapitated.
对 如果是任何
Right. And if it's anything other than
防止掉脑袋之外的用途 那我赢
you specifically not being decapitated by a doorway, I win.
它们不是感知门框用的
They are not for feeling doorways.
我觉得
I think...
它们跟我的共情能力有关
they have something to do with my empathic abilities.
那是什么
What are those?
我触碰别人时 我能感觉到他们的感受
If I touch someone, I can feel their feelings.
- 你会读心术  - 不是
- You read minds?  - No.
心灵感应是感知想法
Telepaths know thoughts.
共情是感知感情
Empaths feel feelings.
情绪
Emotions.
可以吗
May I?
好
All right.
你怀着爱
You feel love.
是的 我怀着一种
Yeah. I guess I feel a general,
- 对所有人的无私的大爱  - 不
- unselfish love for just about everybody.  - No!
是浪漫的 肉欲的爱
Romantic, sexual love.
我才没
No, I don't.
- 爱的是她  - 不
- For her!  - No!
不是
That is not...
好吧
Okay.
她把你最不可告人的秘密说出来了
She just told everyone your deepest, darkest secret!
哥们 拜托 你有点反应过度了
Dude, come on, I think you're overreacting a little bit!
你肯定尴尬死了
You must be so embarrassed!
来感知一下我 试试我
Do me! Do me! Do me!
我从来没感觉过如此的幽默
I have never felt such humor!
真是讨厌到难以置信
So unbelievably uncool.
奎尔
Quill.
敢摸我 你就只能感觉到下巴骨折
Touch me, and the only thing you're gonna feel is a broken jaw.
我也可以稍微改变人的情绪
I can also alter emotions to some extent.
比如
Yeah, like what?
如果我碰到悲伤的人
If I touch someone who is sad...
我可以安抚他们 让他们获得暂时的满足感
I can ease them into contentment for a short while.
我可以让固执的人变顺从
I can make a stubborn person compliant.
但我主要用我的能力帮助主人入睡
But I mostly use it to help my master sleep.
他夜里想着后代 无法入睡
He lies awake at night thinking about his progeny.
在我身上试试那个
Do one of those on me.
睡吧
Sleep.
我喜欢这首歌
I love this song.
在那儿
There!
没了那些玩具 你就没那么厉害了吧
Ain't so tough now without all your toys...
是不是
are you?
闪开
Move!
糟了
Crap.
好啊 耗子
Hey there, rat!
你好吗 你个蓝蠢货
How's it going, you blue idiot?
还不错
Not so bad.
我们接了一份美差
We got ourselves a pretty good little gig here.
有个自命不凡的金闪闪的姑娘
This golden gal with quite a high opinion of herself has
给我们开出很高的价码
offered us a large sum
要我们抓到你和你的同伴交给她
to deliver you and your pals over to her
因为她想杀了你们
because she wants to kill y'all.
你的朋友
Your friend...
敌人太多了
There's too many of them.
他需要我帮忙 要是你在乎他
He needs my help. If you care about him...
你得帮我解开手铐
you need to get me out of these bonds.
他们会杀了他的
They are going to kill him!
告诉你 找到你可容易了
I tell you, it was pretty easy to find you.
山达尔大战的时候 我在你们飞船上
I put a tracer on your ship back there
放了个追踪器
during the war over Xandar.
你保证不伤害格鲁特
Give me your word you won't hurt Groot...
我就告诉你电池在哪
and I'll tell you where the batteries are.
你真走运 我说话不算数
Lucky for you, my word don't mean squat.
不然我就把你们交出去了
Otherwise, I'd actually hand you over.
不然你就什么
Otherwise, you'd what?
我们把电池拿走
We'll take them batteries.
它们值多少 在市场上能卖个二十五万
They're worth what? A quarter mill on the open market?
那个祭司答应给我们一百万
That Priestess offered us a million.
二十五万才三分之一
A quarter is only one third of that!
二十五万不是三分之一
A quarter ain't a third.
二十五万就是二十五
A quarter is 25.
不是
No.
二十五连双靴子都卖不来
We can't even buy a pair of boots with 25 units.
够了
Enough!
重点是 我们没那么蠢
The point is, we ain't stupid enough
会帮忙把银河护卫队杀掉
to help kill the Guardians of the Galaxy!
整个新星军团都不会放过我们的
The whole dang Nova Corps would be on us.
这样不对
That ain't right!
我就说这一次 船长
I just gotta say it this one time, Captain.
不管奎尔背叛你几次
No matter how many times Quill betrays you
你都会保护他 就好像我们其他人都不重要
you protect him like none of the rest of us much matter!
是啊
Yeah!
我才是会支持你的人
I'm the one what sticks up for you!
别激动 克拉林
Take it easy, Kraglin.
说对了 伙计 他是心变软了
Damn straight, lad. He's gone soft.
或许改换个领导人了
Suppose it's time for a change in leadership.
放下你们的枪
Put your damn guns down!
这事肯定是可以和平解决的 各位
There must be some kind of peaceful resolution to this, fellas.
哪怕是武力解决也好 只要我站那边
Or even a violent one where I'm standing over there.
你们好啊 小伙子们
Well, hello, boys.
没熟
It's not ripe.
[伊戈的星球]
各位 欢迎来到我的世界
Welcome, everyone, to my world.
你有自己的星球
You have your own planet?
没什么的 也不比地球的月亮大
Come on. No larger than your Earth's Moon.
谦逊
Humility.
我喜欢
I like it.
我也是个非常谦虚的人
I, too, am extraordinarily humble.
你有自己的星球
You own a planet
还能不穿太空服就干掉几十艘飞船
and can destroy two dozen spaceships without a suit.
你究竟是什么人
What are you exactly?
我是所谓的天神 亲爱的
I'm what's called a Celestial, sweetheart.
天神 你是个神吗
A Celestial, like a god?
就是个普通神 儿子
Small "G," Son.
至少在我跟德拉克斯一样谦逊的日子里是的
At least on the days I'm feeling humble as Drax.
我也不知道我究竟从哪来
I don't know where I came from exactly.
我最初的记忆是闪烁
First thing I remember is flickering
漂浮在宇宙中
adrift in the cosmos utterly
完全孤独地存在着
and entirely alone.
经历了数百万年
Over millions of years
我学会了控制我周围的分子
I learned to control the molecules around me.
我越来越聪明 越来越强大
I grew smarter and stronger.
我不断地建造着
And I continued building from there...
一层又一层
layer by layer...
最终建成了你们现在脚下的星球
the very planet you walk on now.
但我不满足
But I wanted more.
我渴望
I desired...
意义
meaning.
我想着 这宇宙中肯定还有
"There must be some life out there in the universe...
我之外的生命
"Besides just me," I thought.
于是 我立志要找到生命
And so, I set myself the task of finding it.
我创造了
I created...
我所想象的生物生命
what I imagined biological life to be like...
包括最细微的细节
down to the most minute detail.
你做老二了吗
Did you make a penis?
哥们
Dude!
你什么毛病啊
What is wrong with you?
如果他是个星球 怎么能跟你母亲造人啊
If he is a planet, how could he make a baby with your mother?
他会压扁她的
He would smush her!
我不想听我父母是怎么…
I don't need to hear how my parents...
为什么
Why?
我父亲每年冬至
My father would tell the story of
都会讲述他让我母亲怀孕的故事
impregnating my mother every winter solstice.
太恶心了
That's disgusting.
那很美
It was beautiful.
你们地球人真有病
You Earthers have hang-ups.
是啊 德拉克斯 我有老二
Yes, Drax, I got a penis.
谢谢
Thank you!
而且不赖
It's not half bad.
我还有痛觉 消化系统
I've also got pain receptors, and a digestive system and
和所有附带的一切
all the accompanying junk.
我想真正地体验为人
I wanted to experience what it truly meant to be human
于是我探索群星
as I set out amongst the stars...
直到我找到了
until I found...
我所寻找的
what I sought.
生命
Life.
我在这宇宙中终究不是孤独的
I was not alone in the universe after all.
你什么时候认识我母亲的
When did you meet my mother?
不久之后
Not long after.
是梅瑞狄斯让我第一次体验了爱
It was with Meredith that I first experienced love.
我
I
喊她我的水百合
called her my river lily.
那份爱 彼得
And from that love, Peter...
创造了你
you.
我找了你好久
I have searched for you for so long.
当我听说一个地球人
And when I heard of a man from Earth
手握无限宝石还能不死
who held an Infinity Stone in his hand without dying...
我就知道你一定是我所爱的女人的儿子
I knew you must be the son of the woman I loved.
如果你爱她 为什么要离开她
If you loved her, why did you leave her?
这是哗变
This is mutiny!
你们这些渣滓
You're scum!
船长
Captain!
救我啊
Help me! Please!
船长
Captain!
是你害死了那些人
You're the one what killed those men
你领他们走错了路
by leading them down the wrong path.
因为你软弱
Because you're weak.
还愚蠢
And stupid!
现在 掠夺者
It's time for the Ravagers
要再次恢复荣誉 追随新船长
to rise once again to glory with a new captain...
电击脸
Taserface!
抱歉 抱歉 你名叫
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Your name is...
电击脸
It's Taserface?
没错
That's right.
你的脸有电击能力吗
Do you shoot tasers out of your face?
是个比喻
It's metaphorical!
是啊
Yeah!
比喻什么
For what?
比喻
For
这个名字能让任何
it is a name what strikes fear
听到它的人 心生恐惧
into the hearts of anyone what hears it.
嗯
Okay.
好吧
Okay...
随你说吧
whatever you say.
你闭嘴
You shut up.
你就是下一个
You're next.
尤冬塔 我等了好久…
Udonta, I have waited a long time to do...
怎么了
What?
对不起 真对不起
I'm sorry. I am so sorry!
我就是一直在想象 先生 你早上醒来
I just keep imagining you waking up in the morning, sir,
看着镜子
looking in the mirror
严肃地对自己说
and then in all seriousness saying to yourself,
“知道什么名字特别拽吗 电击脸”
"You know what would be a really kick-ass name? Taserface!"
我想象你就是这样
That's how I hear you in my head!
你的第二选择是什么
What was your second choice?
阴囊帽吗
Scrotum Hat?
新计划 我们先杀你
New plan. We're killing you first.
好吧
Well,
死也比做一辈子的
dying is certainly better than having to live an entire life
混蛋白痴 觉得电击脸很酷强
as a moronic shitbag who thinks Taserface is a cool name.
今天就杀到这儿吧
That's enough killing for today.
她是灭霸的女儿
She's the daughter of Thanos.
我以为你是银河系头号的施虐狂
I thought you were the biggest sadist in the galaxy.
那是爸爸雇我的时候
That was when Daddy was paying my bills.
大祭司想亲手杀了那狐狸
The Priestess wants to kill the fox herself.
而至少有十二个克里省在通缉他
And he has bounties on his head in at least 12 Kree provinces.
我保证
I assure you...
我可不像离了魔法棍子的老头子
I am not as easy a mark as an old man without his magic stick...
或会说话的森林野兽那么好对付
or a talking woodland beast.
我要百分之十的赏金
I want 10% of the take...
还有几样东西
and a couple more things.
我们有一整盒的手
We got a whole box of hands...
- 如果那个不行的话  - 挺好的
- if that one don't work out.  - It is fine.
你觉得克里人会处死船长吗
You think them Kree is gonna execute the captain?
克里人自视仁慈 不会让他痛苦的
The Kree consider themselves merciful. It will be painless.
就在这儿 这是我们最好的一艘船
Well, here it is. It's the best ship we got.
伊戈星球的位置发到导航里了
Location of Ego's planet in the nav.
等我们拿到钱就把那百分之十汇给你
We'll wire you the 10% once we's paid.
你打算拿你的那份做什么
What are you gonna do with your share?
我还是孩子时 我父亲会让
As a child, my father would have
我和卡魔拉在训练中对打
Gamora and me battle one another in training.
每次我姐姐赢了
Every time my sister prevailed
我父亲就会把我身体的一部分换成机械
my father would replace a piece of me with machinery
他说是希望我能像她一样强
claiming he wanted me to be her equal.
但她总赢
But she won...
一次又一次 从没一次手下留情
again and again, and again, never once refraining.
所以等我杀了我姐姐
So after I murder my sister...
我要买一艘战舰 装上所有杀戮武器
I will buy a warship with every conceivable instrument of death.
我要像抓狗一样找到我父亲
I will hunt my father like a dog,
然后慢慢把他撕碎
and I will tear him apart slowly
一块一块地拆开
piece by piece...
直到他能稍有体会我每一天所经历的
until he knows some semblance of the profound and unceasing pain
无休止的深刻痛苦
I know every single day.
哦
Yeah.
我想的是买条漂亮项链什么的
I was talking about, like, a pretty necklace.
或是好看的帽子
Or a nice hat. You know,
让其他姑娘都说“哎呀 真漂亮”
something to make the other girls go, "Ooh, that's nice!"
总之 一路顺风
Anyways, happy trails.
我母亲跟所有人说我父亲来自星星
My mother told everyone my father was from the stars.
她有脑瘤 所以大家都以为她是在妄想
She had brain cancer, so everyone thought she was delusional.
彼得
Peter...
听着 我真的很想相信这一切
Listen, I'd love to believe all of this, I really would.
但你离开了这世上最棒的女人
But you left the most wonderful woman ever
让她孤独离世
to die alone.
我并不想离开你母亲的 彼得
I didn't want to leave your mother, Peter.
如果我不定期回到我的星球
If I don't return regularly to my planet
回归其内部的光
and the light within it
这个人形将退化消逝
this form will wither and perish.
那你为什么不回来 你为什么叫勇度去
So why didn't you come back? Why did you send Yondu?
偏偏叫一个罪犯去接我
A criminal, of all people, to come and fetch me?
我是那么爱你母亲 彼得
I loved your mother, Peter!
我无法忍受去一个再没有她的地球
I couldn't stand to set foot on an Earth where she wasn't living!
你无法想象那是什么感觉
You can't imagine what that's like!
我非常清楚那是什么感觉
I know exactly what that feels like!
我不得不看着她死去
I had to watch her die!
我存在了千百万年
Over the millions and millions of years of my existence
犯下了很多错误 彼得
I've made many mistakes, Peter.
但你不是其中之一
But you're not one of them.
请给我个机会
Please give me the chance
做她会希望我做的那种父亲
to be the father she would want me to be.
关于这个星球 和其内部的光
There's so much that I need to teach you about this planet
我有好多要告诉你
and the light within.
那是你的一部分 彼得
They are a part of you, Peter.
什么意思
What do you mean?
给我你的手 儿子
Give me your hands, son.
来
Here.
这样端住
Hold them like that.
好了
Now,
闭上眼睛 集中精神
close your eyes and concentrate.
让思绪进入星球的中心
Take your brain to the center of this planet.
太好了
Yes!
就这样
太好了
Yes! Yes!
- 太棒了 没事  - 怎么回…
- Yes! It's okay.  - What was...
放松 集中精神
Just relax. Concentrate.
你可以的 再来
You can do it. Bring it back.
很好
Yes!
很好 好了 塑形
Yes, yes, now shape it.
感受那股能量
Feel that energy.
就这样
Yes.
你回家了
You're home.
彼得
Peter...
你是怎么来到这颗奇怪 愚蠢的星球上的
How did you get to this weird, dumb planet?
我还是个幼虫时被伊戈发现
Ego found me in my larva state.
我在母星是个孤儿
Orphaned on my homeworld.
他亲手养大了我 把我留在了身边
He raised me by hand, and kept me as his own.
那么你是个宠物
So you're a pet?
大概是吧
I suppose.
人们一般都养可爱的宠物
People usually want cute pets.
伊戈怎么会养个这么面目可憎的
Why would Ego want such a hideous one?
我面目可憎吗
I am hideous?
你简直丑得惊心动魄
You are horrifying to look at. Yes.
但那是好事
But that's a good thing.
如果你长得丑 还有人爱你
When you're ugly, and someone loves you
你知道那人是爱你这个人
you know they love you for who you are.
美丽的人永远不知道谁能信任
Beautiful people never know who to trust.
那我庆幸我很丑
Well, then I'm certainly grateful to be ugly.
那些池塘 让我想起了有次
Those pools, they remind me of a time...
我带女儿去我母星的遗忘湖
when I took my daughter to the forgotten lakes of my homeworld.
她跟你很像
She was like you.
难看吗
Disgusting?
天真无邪
Innocent.
德拉克斯
Drax?
我得告诉你件事
There's something I must tell you.
怎么回事
What's going on?
这位恶心的虫子女士成了我的新朋友
This gross bug lady is my new friend.
我学到了很多事 比如我是个宠物 而且很丑
I'm learning many things, like I'm a pet and ugly.
你不丑 德拉克斯
You're not ugly. Drax!
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
螳螂
Mantis...
你能带我们去我们的住处吗
can you show us where we'll be staying?
这颗星球上怎么没有其他生物
Why are there no other beings on this planet?
这星球就是伊戈
The planet is Ego.
狗不会邀请跳蚤来他背上住
A dog would not invite a flea to live on his back.
你不是跳蚤
And you're not a flea?
我是有用的跳蚤
I'm a flea with a purpose.
我帮他入眠
I help him sleep.
我走出来之前 你正要跟德拉克斯说什么
What were you about to say to Drax before I walked out?
没什么
Nothing.
你们的住处在这边
Your quarters are this way.
我们明早把你们送去给克里人
We deliver you to the Kree in the morning.
之后你俩都活不长了
Neither one of you will last much longer after that.
好啊 电击脸
Okay, Taserface.
替我们跟其他人问好 电击脸
Tell the other guys we said "Hi," Taserface!
这颗小植物呢 要我用石头砸碎它吗
What about this little plant? Can I smash it with a rock?
不行 杰夫
No, Gef.
这么可爱怎么能杀掉
It's too adorable to kill.
送去裁缝那里
Take it to the tailor.
别介意 但你的雇员都是混蛋
No offense, but your employees are a bunch of jerks.
我做了二十年的克里人战奴 是斯塔卡解救了我
I was a Kree battle slave for 20 years when Stakar freed me.
他邀我加入了掠夺者
He offered me a place with the Ravagers.
他说我只需要遵守准则
He said all I needed to do was adhere to the code.
但我年轻
But I was young...
贪心 愚蠢
and greedy, and stupid.
就像你 偷了那些电池
Like you stealing those batteries.
那更多是德拉克斯干的
That was mostly Drax.
我和斯塔卡 还有其他船长
Me and Stakar and the other captains...
我们跟你和你的朋友很像
we weren't so different from you and your friends.
那是我唯一的家庭
The only family I ever had.
我违反准则后
When I broke the code...
他们流放了我
they exiled me.
我活该如此
This is what I deserve.
等等 矫情女王
Slow down, drama queen.
你或许是活该 但我不是
You might deserve this, but I don't.
我们得逃出去
We gotta get outta here.
奎尔呢
Where's Quill?
他跟他老爸走了
He went off with his old man.
- 伊戈  - 对
- Ego?  - Yeah.
今天净是些蠢蛋名字
It's a day for dumbass names.
你笑了 就那么一刻 我有种温暖的感觉
You're smiling. And for a second, I got a warm feeling.
但你那一口烂牙毁了这感觉
But then it was ruined by those disgusting-ass teeth.
你是职业混蛋吗
You like a professional asshole or what?
挺专业的反正
Pretty much a pro.
你为什么没像说好的那样把奎尔送去给伊戈
Why didn't you deliver Quill to Ego like you promised?
他很瘦小
He was skinny.
能钻进我们钻不进的地方 适合偷盗
Could fit into places we couldn't. Good for thievin'.
我知道我们怎么出去了
I got an idea on how to get outta here.
但我需要你的小朋友
But we're gonna need your little friend.
吉祥物 吉祥物
Mascot, mascot, mascot...
小家伙好激动 该喝一杯
Little fellow's all worked up! He needs a drink!
看他气成那样多可爱
Look how cute it is when it's all riled up.
他太有趣了
He's goddang precious!
小树枝
Hey, twig!
过来
Come here.
Come on.
天呐 他们把你怎么了
Man... what did they do to you?
你想帮我们出去吗
You wanna help us get outta here?
我需要你去找样东西 然后拿来给我
There's something I need you to get, and bring back to me.
在船长室 有个原型机机械鳍
In the captain's quarters, there's a prototype fin...
就是我脑袋上戴的那玩意
the thing I wore on my head.
床铺旁边有个抽屉 就在里面 红色的
There's a drawer next to the bunk. It's in that. It's red.
懂了吗
You got it?
那是我的内裤
That's my underwears.
嗯 我就觉得
Yeah, I was pretty sure
他根本就没听懂你说什么
he didn't know what you were talkin' about.
你得解释得更细致点
You have to explain it more careful.
是个原型机机械鳍
It's a prototype fin.
那是只奥罗尼 机械鳍 格鲁特
That's an orloni. It's a fin, Groot.
这次你来解释
You explain it this time.
好吧
All right.
那是沃克的眼睛
That's Vorker's eye.
他睡觉时会拿下来
He takes it out when he sleeps.
去 再找
Go. Look again.
把眼睛留下
But leave the eye here.
干吗
Why?
等他明早醒来
He's gonna wake up tomorrow
会不知道
and he's not gonna know
他的眼睛去哪了
where his eye is!
那是张桌子
That's a desk.
我们说了那玩意才这么大
We told you it was this big.
拜托告诉我你们船上有个冰箱
Tell me you guys have a refrigerator somewhere
里面全是切下来的人脚趾
with a bunch of severed human toes.
好吧 那我们说好永远不再提这事了
Okay. Then let's just agree to never discuss this.
你要打开的抽屉 上面有这个标志
The drawer you wanna open has this symbol on it.
好吗
Okay?
什么 不
What? No!
他以为你要他把那个当帽子戴
He thinks you want him to wear it as a hat.
我不是那么说的
That's not what I said!
- 我是格鲁特  - 他很庆幸你不要求他那么做
- I am Groot.  - He's relieved you don't want him to.
- 我是格鲁特  - 他讨厌帽子
- I am Groot.  - He hates hats.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
讨厌任何人戴帽子 不仅是他自己
On anyone, not just himself.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
你还以为谁的脑袋形状很怪
One minute you think someone has a weird-shaped head
结果转眼发现
the next minute it's just because
原来那脑袋上戴了顶帽子
you realize part of that head is the hat.
所以你才不喜欢帽子
That's why you don't like hats?
这些话非得现在说吗
This is an important conversation right now?
不是那个
That ain't it.
我并没想哗变的
I didn't mean to do a mutiny.
他们杀了我所有的朋友
They killed all my friends.
准备释放第三飞行舱
Get the third quadrant ready for release.
还有件事
One more thing.
船上有奎尔那些老歌的备份吗
You got any clones of Quill's old music on the ship?
他拿走了
He's got it!
勇度拿走了机械鳍
Yondu's got the fin!
上
Go!
下面
Down there!
你个疯子
You maniac.
你会炸掉整艘船的
The whole ship's gonna blow.
不会是整艘船
Not the whole ship.
你是谁
Who is this?
我要把勇度的飞船的坐标发你
I am sending you the coordinates for Yondu's ship.
- 释放飞行舱  - 是 船长
- Release the quadrant!  - Aye, Captain!
我只求一件事
I only ask one thing.
你们的大祭司
That your High Priestess
要告诉他是谁注定了他的毁灭
tell him the name of the man what sealed his fate.
电击脸
Taserface!
去哪 船长
Where to, Captain?
伊戈
Ego.
不行
No, boy!
对于哺乳类来说
It ain't healthy for a mammalian body
一下跳跃五十次以上对身体有害
to hop more than 50 jumps at a time.
我知道
I know that.
我们要跳七百次了
We are about to do 700!
那么这一切有一天都可能属于我喽
So I guess this could all be mine someday.
火箭 火箭 你在吗
Rocket? Rocket, are you there?
你在干什么 彼得
What are you doing, Peter?
跟我跳舞吧
Dance with me.
我才不跟你跳舞
I'm not going to dance with you.
这是山姆·库克的歌
This is Sam Cooke
他可是地球最伟大的歌手之一
one of the greatest Earth singers of all time.
德拉克斯觉得你不是个舞者
Drax thinks you're not a dancer.
你要是敢把这件事说出去
If you ever tell anyone about this...
我就杀了你
I will kill you.
我们什么时候处理一下
When are we gonna do something about this
我们之间心照不宣的情愫啊
unspoken thing between us?
什么心照不宣的情愫
What unspoken thing?
就是
This...
像《欢乐酒店》里 萨姆和黛安那样
Cheers, Sam and Diane...
电视剧里相互喜欢的一男一女
a guy and a girl on a TV show who dig each other...
但他们从不说破 否则收视率就要下降了
but never say it because if they do, the ratings would go down...
就这种的
sort of thing.
才没有什么心照不宣的情愫
There's no unspoken thing.
这是二十二条军规 如果你说了
Well, it's a catch-22, because if you said it,
那就不叫心照不宣了
then it would be spoken
那你就是撒谎了 所以你不说
and you would be a liar. So, by not saying it...
反而是在说实话 也就是承认有
you are telling the truth, and admitting that there is.
不 我不是那个…
No, that's not what I...
我们现在应该说的
What we should be discussing right now
是这地方
is something about this place.
有点不对劲
It doesn't feel right.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
是你希望我来的
You're the one who wanted me to come here!
那个螳螂女
That girl Mantis
她在怕什么
she's afraid of something.
你为什么要夺走这一切
Why are you trying to take this away from me?
我没有…
I'm not trying...
他是我父亲 是我的血亲
He's my father. He's blood.
你在地球也有血亲 你可不想回那儿去
You have blood on Earth and you never wanted to return there.
再说一遍 是你逼我来的
Again, you made me come here!
而且地球 地球是我母亲死在我面前的地方
And Earth, Earth is the place where my mother died in front of me.
不 是因为那里是真实的 这里只是个幻想
No, it's because that place is real, and this is a fantasy.
这是真的 我是个半人 记得吗
This is real! I'm only half human, remember?
我担心的就是那一半
That's the half I'm worried about.
我懂了 你嫉妒
I get it. You're jealous
因为我是半神 而你喜欢我比较弱的时候
because I'm part-god, and you like when I'm the weak one.
你本就让人难以忍受
You were insufferable to begin with.
我一直联系不上火箭
I haven't been able to reach Rocket.
我要出去 看看能不能搜到信号
I'm gonna go outside, and I'm gonna try and get a signal.
知道吗 这根本不是《欢乐酒店》
You know what? This is not Cheers after all!
在这部剧里
This is whatever the show is
一个人愿意敞开心扉面对新的前景
where one person is willing to open themselves up to new possibility,
而另一个人却是个混蛋
and the other person is a jerk
不信任任何人
who doesn't trust anybody!
这是部不存在的剧
It's a show that doesn't exist.
所以它不会有任何收视率
That's why it would get zero ratings!
我不知道《欢乐酒店》是什么
I don't know what Cheers is!
我终于找到我的家人了 你不懂吗
I finally found my family. Don't you understand that?
我以为你已经有家人了
I thought you already had.
该死
Damn it.
神经病
Psychopath!
你搞什么
Are you kidding me?
我赢了
I win.
我赢了 我打败了你
I win. I bested you in combat.
不 是我救了你
No. I saved your life.
你留我一命真是太蠢了
Well, you were stupid enough to let me live.
是你没下杀手
You let me live!
我不需要你总想打赢我
I don't need you always trying to beat me!
我可没刚刚穿越宇宙
I'm not the one that just flew across the universe
就为了争个输赢
just because I wanted to win.
用不着你告诉我我要什么
Do not tell me what I want.
我不用告诉你你要什么
I don't need to tell you what you want!
明摆着的
It's obvious!
你才是想赢的那个 我只想要个姐姐
You were the one who wanted to win. And I just wanted a sister!
我只有你
You were all I had.
但你总想赢
But you were the one who needed to win.
灭霸把我的眼睛挖出来
Thanos pulled my eye from my head
把我的大脑取出来
and my brain from my skull
把我的胳膊拽下来
and my arm from my body
都是因为你
because of you.
你没事吧 儿子
You all right, son?
我之前看见你女朋友怒气冲冲地走了
I saw your girl stomp off a little earlier in quite a huff.
是啊
Yeah.
你听这首歌真巧
It's fortuitous you listening to this song.
- 你知道…  - 《布兰迪》
- You know...  - Brandy?
镜子组合的
By Looking Glass?
是你妈妈的最爱
A favorite of your mom's.
是啊
Yeah, it was.
是地球最伟大的音乐作品之一
One of Earth's greatest musical compositions.
也许就是最伟大的
Perhaps its very greatest.
说得太对了
Yeah, yes!
彼得 你我就是那首歌里的水手
Peter, you and I, we're the sailor in that song.
他在一个夏日出现
He came on a summer's day.
带来远方的礼物
Bringing gifts from far away.
就像我让你妈妈怀上的那个孩子
Like the child I put in your mother...
或是你给卡魔拉的自由
or the freedom you brought Gamora.
布兰迪 你是个好姑娘
Brandy, you're a fine girl.
你肯定会是个好妻子
What a good wife you would be.
我的生活 我的爱
My life, my love.
我的女人是大海
My lady is the sea.
大海召唤着水手
The sea calls the sailor back.
他爱那姑娘 但那里不是他的天地
He loves the girl, but that's not his place.
大海召唤他 就像历史召唤伟人
The sea calls upon him as history calls upon great men.
有时我们无法享受凡人的乐趣
And sometimes we are deprived the pleasures of mortals.
你可能不是凡人 但我
Well, you may not be mortal, but me...
不 彼得
No, Peter...
只要这颗星球内的光不熄
death will remain a stranger to both of us
我们就都不用面对死亡
as long as the light burns within the planet.
我可以永生不死
I'm immortal?
真的吗
Really?
对 只要光还在
Yes! As long as the light exists.
我可以用那光建造很酷的东西 就像
And I can use the light to build cool things like
你当初建造这颗星球那样
how you made this whole planet?
你可能要花几百万年时间去练习
It might take you a few million years of practice
才能得心应手 但 没错
before you get really good at it. But, yes!
什么 这太
What! This is...
准备见识一个八百英尺的吃豆人雕像吧
Well, get ready for an 800-foot statue of Pac-Man
旁边还有骷髅王[动画形象]和希瑟·拉克里尔[女星]
with Skeletor and Heather Locklear.
你想干什么都行
You can do anything you want.
我要做一些奇怪的东西
I'm gonna make some weird shit.
但是 彼得 这是巨大的责任
But you know, Peter, it is a tremendous responsibility.
只有我们能重塑宇宙
Only we can remake the universe.
只有我们能牵着宇宙的缰绳
Only we can take the bridle of the cosmos
领导它走向正确的方向
and lead it to where it needs to go.
怎么做
How?
跟我来
Come with me.
德拉克斯 德拉克斯
Drax, Drax. Drax!
德拉克斯 我们得谈谈
Drax! We need to talk.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
但我喜欢稍微有点肉的女人
But I like a woman with some meat on her bones.
什么
What?
我说我觉得你恶心
I tried to let you down easily
就是不想让你太伤心
by telling you I found you disgusting.
不 我不是想…
No, that's not what I...
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在想象跟你有肌肤之亲
I'm imagining being with you physically.
德拉克斯 我不是想
Drax... That's not...
我对你不是那种喜欢
I don't like you like that.
我都不喜欢你这个物种
I don't even like the type of thing you are.
没必要人身攻击
There's no need to get personal.
听着 伊戈得到了他想要的
Listen! Ego's gotten exactly what he wanted.
我应该早点告诉你的
I should have told you earlier.
我真傻
I'm stupid.
你们有危险了
You are in danger.
那是什么
What is that?
你得重新调整你看待生命的方式
Now, you need to readjust the way you process life.
我们身边的一切 包括那个姑娘
Everything around us, including the girl...
一切都是暂时的
Everything is temporary.
我们才是永恒
We are forever.
永恒不会无聊吗
Doesn't eternity get boring?
如果你有目标就不会 彼得
Not if you have a purpose, Peter,
你来这儿就是为了那个目标
which is why you're here.
我告诉过你 很多年前
I told you how all those years ago
我有一股不灭的冲动 想找到生命
I had an unceasing impulse to find life.
但我没告诉你的是
But what I did not tell you was how,
当我终于找到它的时候
when I finally did find it...
它是那么的
it was all so...
令人失望
disappointing.
那时我才
And that is when I came...
深深地顿悟了
to a profound realization.
我内心寻找其他生命的渴望
My innate desire to seek out other life
不是为了让我能游走于那生命之间
was not so that I could walk among that life.
彼得
Peter...
我找到了意义
I have found meaning.
我看见了
I see it.
永恒
Eternity!
天啊
Oh, my God.
我们得离开这颗星球
We need to get off this planet.
天啊
Oh, man.
总之 我被粗鲁地打断之前我正在说…
Anyway, before I was so rudely interrupted...
那时 我是个联邦快递的快递员
At that time, I was a Federal Express man.
你干什么呢 小子
What the hell you doing, boy?
从你说到他时的样子我看得出
I could tell by how you talked about him
这个伊戈不是好人
this Ego is bad news.
我们得来救奎尔
We're here to save Quill.
为了什么
For what?
荣誉吗
For honor?
爱吗
For love?
不 我才不在乎那些
No. I don't care about those things.
我想救奎尔 好证明我比他强
I wanna save Quill so I can prove I'm better than him!
我能拿这事压他一辈子
I can lord this over him forever.
你笑我做什么
What are you laughing at me for?
你可以骗自己和其他所有人 但你骗不了我
You can fool yourself and everyone else, but you can't fool me.
我了解你
I know who you are.
你才不了解我呢 废物
You don't know anything about me, loser.
我了解你的一切
I know everything about you.
我知道你假装是最坏最狠的人
I know you play like you're the meanest and the hardest,
但你其实最害怕
but, actually, you're the most scared of all.
闭嘴
Shut up!
我知道你偷你用不着的电池
I know you steal batteries you don't need
你推开每一个愿意忍受你的人
and you push away anyone who's willing to put up with you
因为哪怕一点点爱
because just a little bit of love
也会提醒你 你内心的空虚多大多深
reminds you how big and empty that hole inside you actually is.
我叫你闭嘴了
I said shut up!
我知道那些制造了你的科学家
I know them scientists what made you,
根本没在乎过你
never gave a rat's ass about you.
我说真的 哥们
I'm serious, dude!
就像我自己的父母 他们把我
Just like my own damn parents who sold me
他们的亲生儿子 卖去做奴隶
their own little baby, into slavery.
我知道你是什么人 小子
I know who you are, boy.
因为你是我
Because you're me.
我们是一对儿什么样的人啊
What kind of a pair are we?
大概是一对儿要去对付一颗星球的人吧
The kind that's about to go fight a planet, I reckon.
好啊 好嘞 很好
All right, okay! Good.
等等
Wait.
对付什么
Fight a what?
你们是什么人
Who are you people?
这地方是什么
What is this place?
卡魔拉 放了她
Gamora, let her go!
洞里的尸体 他们是谁
The bodies in the caverns... Who are they?
你在害怕
You are scared.
我称之为扩张
I call it the Expansion.
这是我的目标
It is my purpose
现在
and now
它也是你的目标了
it is yours as well.
好美啊
It's beautiful.
数千年来
Over thousands of years,
我将数千个我的延伸根植在了
I implanted thousands of extensions of myself
数千个世界上
on thousands of worlds.
我得实现生命唯一真正的目标
I need to fulfill life's one true purpose...
生长 传播
To grow and spread
覆盖一切存在
covering all that exists
直到一切都
until everything is...
变成我
Me!
她对我做了什么
What did she do to me?
她已经把一切都告诉我了
She already told me everything.
我只有一个问题
I only had one problem.
一个天神
A single Celestial
是没有足够能量完成这样的伟业的
doesn't have enough power for such an enterprise.
但两个天神
But two Celestials...
那或许就可以了
Well, now, that just might do.
那些尸体
The bodies...
都是他的孩子
are his children.
我所做的一切中
Out of all my labors
我最喜欢的
the most beguiling
就是尝试将我的DNA嫁接到其他物种上
was attempting to graft my DNA with that of another species.
我原本希望这样的配对
I hoped the result of such a coupling
足以为扩张提供能量
would be enough to power the Expansion.
我让勇度把一些后代送来给我
I had Yondu deliver some of them to me.
这有违掠夺者的准则
It broke the Ravager code,
但我慷慨地赔偿了他
but I compensated him generously and
而且为安抚他的良心 我说我绝不会伤害他们
to ease his conscience, I said I'd never hurt them.
这倒不假 他们都毫无感觉
I mean, that was true. They never felt a thing.
但他们一个个都让我失望了
But one after the other, they failed me.
没有一个携带了天神基因
Not one of them carried the Celestial genes.
直到你 彼得
Until you, Peter.
我所有的后裔里
Out of all my spawn,
只有你继承了与光的联系
only you carried the connection to the light.
我们得马上找到彼得 离开这个破星球
We need to find Peter now, and get off this damn planet.
伊戈现在肯定已经拉拢了他
Ego will have won him to his side by now.
- 他有办法…  - 那我们直接走吧
- He has a way of...  - Then we just go.
不行
No!
他是我们的朋友
He's our friend.
你们就成天冲彼此大吼
All any of you do is yell at each other.
你们才不是朋友
You are not friends.
你是对的
You're right.
我们是家人
We're family.
我们不丢下任何人
We leave no one behind.
或许除了你
Except maybe you.
天呐
Oh, my God.
我存在以来首次
For the first time in my existence,
真正不再孤单了
I am truly not alone!
怎么了 儿子
What is it, son?
我的朋友们
My friends.
你瞧 这就是你人性的一面 彼得
You see, that's the mortal in you, Peter.
是啊
Yes.
我们超越了那些东西
We are beyond such things.
是啊
Yes.
- 好了…  - 但我母亲…
- Now...  - But my mother...
你说你爱我母亲的
You said you loved my mother.
我是爱她
And that I did.
我的水百合
My river lily who knew
她会唱收音机里播放的每一首歌
all the words to every song that came over the radio.
我三次回到地球看她
I returned to Earth to see her three times.
我知道 如果我再第四次回去
And I knew if I returned a fourth...
我就再不会走了
I'd never leave.
扩张
The Expansion...
我存在的目的 就完了
the reason for my very existence, would be over.
所以我做了我必须做的
So, I did what I had to do.
但是
But
让她患上脑瘤简直伤透了我的心
it broke my heart to put that tumor in her head.
什么
What?
好吧
Now, all right...
我知道这听上去很不好
I know that sounds bad.
你
Who
以为你是谁啊
in the hell do you think you are?
你杀了我母亲
You killed my mother!
我
I tried...
那么努力
so hard...
找到最适合你的形态
to find the form that best suited you...
这就是你的感谢吗
and this is the thanks I get?
你真得长大了
You really need to grow up.
我本想跟你一起做的
I wanted to do this together...
但看来你只能
but I suppose you'll have to learn
做个一千年的电池 慢慢长进了
by spending the next thousand years as a battery!
可算 火箭
Finally! Rocket?
把发射器带在身边 我好找你
Keep that transmitter nearby, so I can find you.
我们在一件旧施工设备里
We're in an old piece of construction equipment
勇度曾用它来切开艾斯克维拉银行
Yondu once used to slice open the Bank of A'askavaria.
伊戈是个疯子
Ego's unhinged.
我知道 准备好
I know. Get ready.
放 克拉林
Drop her, Kraglin.
不
No.
我的生命 我的爱
My life, my love.
我的女人是大海
My lady is the sea
彼得
Peter...
这就是那海
this is the sea.
你好啊 混蛋
Hey, there, jackass!
那是什么玩意
What is that thing?
闪开 小笨格鲁特
Out of the way, dumber, smaller Groot!
我就说有点不对劲
I told you something didn't feel right.
“我早说过”我现在正需要听这种话
"I told you so." Just what I need to hear right now.
我不是回来了吗
Well, I came back, didn't I?
因为我们有心照不宣的情愫
Because there's an unspoken thing.
才没有什么心照不宣的情愫
There is no unspoken thing.
你干什么呢 你差点害死我们
What are you doing? You could've killed us all!
“谢谢 火箭”
"Thank you, Rocket"?
我们都控制局面了
We had it under control.
我们没有 那只是他真身的延伸
We did not. That is only an extension of his true self.
他很快就会回来的
He will be back soon.
蓝妹妹怎么在这儿
What's Smurfette doing here?
我只想搭车回家
Whatever I need to do to get a damn ride home.
她还想杀我
She tried to murder me!
我救了你 你个蠢狐狸
I saved you, you stupid fox!
他不是狐狸
He's not a fox.
- 我是格鲁特  - 我也不是浣兔
- I am Groot.  - I'm not a raboon, either.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
是“浣熊” 算了
"Raccoon." Whatever.
怎么杀一个天神啊
How do we kill a Celestial?
他有个核
There's a center to him.
他的大脑还是灵魂什么的
His brain, his soul, whatever it is...
有个保护壳
Some sort of protective shell.
在地表下的洞穴里
It's in the caverns below the surface.
勇度
Yondu?
推进器失去动力了
Thrusters are out.
看来我该庆幸我长得瘦
Guess I should be glad I was a skinny kid.
否则你就会把我交给这个疯子了
Otherwise, you'd have delivered me to this maniac.
你还以为那是我留下了你的原因吗 白痴
You still reckon that's the reason I kept you around, you idiot?
是你这么跟我说的 你个老笨蛋
That's what you told me, you old doofus.
我搞明白了其他孩子的下场后
Once I figured out what happened to them other kids
我当然不能把你交出去
I wasn't just gonna hand you over.
你说你要吃了我
You said you were gonna eat me.
那是玩笑话
That was being funny!
我可没想笑
Not to me!
你们真有毛病
You people have issues.
我当然有毛病
Of course I have issues.
那可是我老爸
That's my freakin' father!
推进器恢复了
Thrusters are back up.
- 我们该向上飞  - 不行
- We should be going up!  - We can't!
伊戈想毁掉我们所知的宇宙
Ego wants to eradicate the universe as we know it.
我们得杀了他
We have to kill him.
火箭
Rocket!
好嘞
Got it!
那我们又要拯救银河系了
So, we're saving the galaxy again?
大概是吧
I guess.
太棒了
Awesome!
如果我们救了两次银河系
We're really gonna be able to jack up our prices
就能坐地起价了
if we're two-time galaxy savers.
我真不敢相信你居然想到了这个
I seriously can't believe that's where your mind goes.
就是想想嘛 哥们 我们不是朋友嘛
It was just a random thought, man. I thought we were friends.
我当然在乎那些星球啊 建筑啊
Of course, I care about the planets, and the buildings
和各个星球上的动物啊
and all the animals on the planets.
还有人呢
And the people.
那个坏脾气狗狗好可爱 他让我想死
The crabby puppy is so cute. He makes me wanna die!
飞行员
Pilots...
释放先遣队
release envoy units.
我们的传感器感应到电池在星球地表下
Our sensors detect the batteries are below the surface of the planet.
下潜
Dive!
船长
Captain?
伊戈为什么找你来
Tell me why Ego wants you here?
他需要我跟光的基因联系
He needs my genetic connection to the light
来帮他毁灭宇宙
to help destroy the universe.
他还想教我控制能量
He tried to teach me how to control the power.
你能控制吗
So, could you?
稍稍能吧
A little.
我做了个能量球
I made a ball.
球
A ball?
我已经拼命去想了
I thought as hard as I could.
我只能弄出来个那个
It was all that I could come up with.
你“想”
You "thought"?
你以为我控制这支箭飞的时候
You think when I make this arrow fly
是用的脑袋吗
I use my head?
那儿
There.
那就是伊戈的核
That's Ego's core.
外壳很厚 火箭
That ore is thick, Rocket.
交给我吧
I got it covered.
我们必须快点
We must hurry.
伊戈很快就会找到我们
It will not take Ego long to find us.
稳住
Keep it steady.
钻透到核 然后杀死他
We drill into the center, we kill him!
船长
Captain?
怎么了 克拉林
What is it, Kraglin?
还记得阿耶莎那妞儿吗
Remember that Ayesha chick?
记得 怎么了
Yeah, why?
该死
Oh, hell!
你为什么不开激光炮
Why aren't you firing the lasers?
他们炸掉了发电机
They blew out the generator.
我记得我带了一个小引爆器
I think I packed a small detonator.
有引爆器没炸药也没用
A detonator is worthless without explosives.
我们有这些
Well, we got these.
这玩意的破坏性能杀死伊戈吗
Is that thing strong enough to kill Ego?
如果能的话 会造成他整个
If it is, it'll cause a chain reaction
神经系统的连锁反应
throughout his entire nervous system.
意思是
Meaning what?
整颗星球都会爆炸
The entire planet will explode.
我们得快点逃出去
We'll have to get out of here fast.
我装了个定时器
I rigged a timer.
走
Go!
他要来了
He's coming.
你不是说你能让他睡着吗
Didn't you say you could make him sleep?
在他想睡的时候 他太强大了
When he wants. He's too powerful.
我做不到
I can't!
你不用相信自己
You don't have to believe in yourself
因为我相信你
because I believe in you.
睡吧
Sleep!
我没想到她能做到
I never thought she'd be able to do it
毕竟她一副很瘦弱的样子
with as weak and skinny as she appears to be.
我不知道我能拖住他多久
I don't know how long I can hold him.
金属太厚了
The metal's too thick.
要让炸弹达到目的
For the bomb to work,
我们得把它放在伊戈的核上
we'd actually need to place it on Ego's core.
我们的大屁股钻不进这些小洞里
And our fat butts ain't gonna fit through those tiny holes.
那么
Well...
这主意糟透了
That's a terrible idea.
我们就剩这一个主意了
Which is the only kind of idea we have left.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
“火箭 做这个 火箭 做那个”
"Rocket, do this. Rocket, do that."
今天真够受的
What a day.
好了 首先你打开这个开关 再打开这个
All right, first you flick this switch, then this switch.
这样就启动了
That activates it.
接着你按下这个按钮
Then you push this button
让你有五分钟时间逃跑
which will give you five minutes to get out of there.
不管你做什么
Now, whatever you do
千万别按这个按钮
don't push this button
因为那样会立即引爆炸弹
because that will set off the bomb immediately
我们就都没命了
and we'll all be dead.
重复一遍我刚才说的
Now, repeat back what I just said.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
- 我是格鲁特  - 对了
- I am Groot.  - That's right.
- 我是格鲁特  - 不
- I am Groot.  - No!
不对 这个按钮会杀死所有人
No, that's the button that will kill everyone!
再来
Try again.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
不 你刚才就是这么错的
No! That's exactly what you just said!
这怎么可能
How is that even possible?
你应该按哪个按钮
Which button is the button you're supposed to push?
指一下
Point to it.
不对
No!
你让他紧张了
You're making him nervous!
闭嘴 给我拿点胶带来
Shut up and get me some tape!
外面有人有胶带吗
Does anybody have any tape out there?
我要把死亡按钮贴上胶带
I wanna put some tape over the death button.
我没胶带 我去问问
I don't have any tape. Let me check.
勇度 你有…
Yo, Yondu... do you have...
你有胶带吗
Do you have any tape?
卡魔拉 你有胶带吗
Gamora? Do you have any tape?
胶带
Tape!
算了
Never mind.
德拉克斯 你有胶带吗
Drax, do you have any tape?
对 透明胶也行
Yes, scotch tape would work.
既然你没有 为什么还要问我
Then why did you ask me if scotch tape would work,
透明胶行不行
if you don't have any?
没人有胶带
Nobody has any tape!
谁都没有胶带吗
Not a single person has tape?
没有
Nope!
你问过星云了吗
Did you ask Nebula?
问过了
Yes!
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我问勇度的时候
I asked Yondu...
- 她就坐在他旁边  - 我就知道你撒谎
- and she was sitting next to him.  - I knew you were lying!
你包里装着价值连城的电池还有一枚原子弹
You have priceless batteries and an atomic bomb in your bag.
要说谁会带胶带 就是你了
If anybody's gonna have tape, it's you!
我就想说这个 什么事都得我做
That's exactly my point! I have to do everything!
你浪费了多少时间
You are wasting a lot of time here!
我们都要死了
We're all gonna die.
后推进器又坏了
Rear thrusters are out again!
没那个发电机我们死定了
We're done for without that generator!
银河护卫队
Guardians...
也许这对你们会是个安慰
perhaps it will provide you solace
你们的死 不会毫无意义
that your deaths are not without purpose.
而是会警告那些
They will serve as a warning
想要背叛我们的人
to all of those tempted with betraying us.
别想耍索维林族
Don't screw with the Sovereign.
会很疼的
This is gonna hurt.
光说不练
Promises, promises.
不
No!
不不不
No! No! No!
要爆炸了
We're gonna blow!
彼得 不
Peter! No!
怎么了
What?
你活像玛丽·波平斯
You look like Mary Poppins.
他酷吗
Is he cool?
当然 他很酷
Hell, yeah, he's cool.
我是玛丽·波平斯哦
I'm Mary Poppins, y'all!
螳螂 小心
Mantis, look out!
她只是昏过去了
She's just unconscious.
炸弹还有多久炸
How long until the bomb goes off?
万一万一格鲁特没把我们都炸死
In the unlikely event that Groot doesn't kill us all...
那还有六分钟
about six minutes.
克拉林 我们需要飞行舱来带我们撤离
Kraglin, we need the quadrant for an extraction.
倒计时五分钟
T-minus five minutes.
是 船长
Aye, Captain.
克拉林到时 上面得有人接应
Somebody's gotta be up top when Kraglin arrives.
德拉克斯 带螳螂走
Drax, take Mantis.
我的乳头
My nipples!
卡魔拉
Gamora!
彼得
Peter!
别想多了
Get over it.
得了 彼得 我知道你并不想这样
Come now, Peter. I know this isn't what you want.
我让你做出这样的选择 还算什么父亲啊
What kind of father would I be to let you make this choice?
帅气
Yeah!
很快 彼得 我们就将成为一切
Soon, Peter, we will be all there is.
别再惹我生气了
So stop pissing me off!
我们得上去撤离点
We have to get up to the extraction point!
冲
Go!
我说过
I told you...
我不想一个人做
I don't want to do this alone.
你不能拒绝
You cannot deny
宇宙赋予你的人生目的
the purpose the universe has bestowed upon you.
大家不要靠近
Everyone, I need you to stay back!
那是什么
What is that?
不非得如此的 彼得
It doesn't need to be like this, Peter.
你为什么要毁掉我们的机会
Why are you destroying our chance?
别再否认自己的身份了
Stop pretending you aren't what you are.
你是上亿
One in billions.
上兆 甚至更多中的唯一
Trillions. Even more.
生命怎么可能有更伟大的意义
What greater meaning can life possibly have to offer?
我不是用脑袋控制箭的 孩子
I don't use my head to fly the arrow, boy!
我是用心
I use my heart...
你不该杀了我妈妈 还捏碎我的随身听
You shouldn't have killed my mom, and squished my Walkman.
格鲁特 如果你听得到 快点
Groot? If you can hear me, hurry up!
我不确定奎尔还能分散他注意力多久
I'm not sure how long Quill can keep him distracted!
格鲁特 快点
Groot, hurry!
勇度 我们要炸了
Yondu, we're about to blow!
上船
Get to the ship!
不能丢下奎尔
Not without Quill!
你还得照顾小树枝
You need to take care of the twig!
不能丢下你
Not without you!
我这辈子都没做过几件好事 耗子
I ain't done nothin' right my whole damn life, rat.
让我做这件吧
You need to give me this.
一套太空服和一个飞行装置
A spacesuit and an aero-rig.
我一样只有一个
I only have one of each.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
他说什么
What's that?
他说“欢迎加入他娘的银河护卫队”
He says, "Welcome to the frickin' Guardians of the Galaxy."
而且他用的词不是“他娘的”
Only he didn't use "Frickin'."
再见 小树枝
Bye, twig.
我们回头得好好谈谈你说粗话的问题
We're gonna need to have a real discussion about your language.
彼得呢
Where's Peter?
火箭 他在哪
Rocket, where is he?
火箭
Rocket.
火箭 看着我 他在哪
Rocket, look at me! Where is he?
不 我不能丢下他
No. I'm not leaving without him.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我今天只能承受失去一个朋友
I can only afford to lose one friend today.
克拉林 走
Kraglin, go!
等等
Wait...
奎尔回来了吗
Is Quill back?
火箭 奎尔呢
Rocket, where's Quill?
火箭
Rocket!
奎尔呢
Where's Quill?
不 我们得阻止它
No, we need to stop it.
我们得阻止它
We need to stop it.
不 停下
No. Stop.
停下 听着 听我说
Stop. Listen. Listen to me!
你是个神
You are a god.
如果你杀了我
If you kill me...
你就跟其他人一样了
you'll be just like everybody else.
那有什么不好
What's so wrong with that?
不
No!
他或许是你生父 孩子 但他可不是你爸爸
He may have been your father, boy, but he wasn't your daddy.
真抱歉我一件事都没做对
I'm sorry I didn't do none of it right.
你是我的孩子我太走运了
I'm damn lucky you're my boy.
什么
What?
勇度 你干什么
Yondu, what are you doing?
不行
You can't.
勇度
Yondu!
不
No!
不不
No! No!
不要
No!
我告诉卡魔拉
I told Gamora
我小时候
how when I was a kid
会假装大卫·霍索夫是我爸爸
I used to pretend David Hasselhoff was my dad.
他是地球的一个歌手演员 很出名
He's a singer and actor from Earth, really famous guy.
刚刚 我突然想到
Earlier, it struck me...
勇度没有会说话的车 但他有会飞的箭
Yondu didn't have a talking car, but he did have a flying arrow.
他没有天使般美丽的歌喉
He didn't have the beautiful voice of an angel
但他的哨声有如天籁
but he did have the whistle of one.
勇度和大卫·霍索夫都会经历牛逼的冒险
Both Yondu and David Hasselhoff went on kick-ass adventures
勾搭性感的女人
and hooked up with hot women
还打机器人
and fought robots.
看来大卫·霍索夫终究成为了我爸爸
I guess David Hasselhoff did kind of end up being my dad after all.
但其实那是你 勇度
Only it was you, Yondu.
我有个很酷的爸爸
I had a pretty cool dad.
我想说的是
What I'm trying to say here is...
有时候你寻找了一生的东西
sometimes that thing you're searching for your whole life
其实一直在你身边
it's right there by your side all along.
你却不自知
You don't even know it.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
他是喊你小树枝
He did call you twig.
星云
Nebula...
我跟你一样只是个孩子
I was a child like you.
我每天只想着活到第二天
I was concerned with staying alive until the next day, every day.
我从未想过灭霸对你做了什么
And I never considered what Thanos was doing to you.
我想弥补
I'm trying to make it right.
整个宇宙中还有其他你这样的小女孩
There are little girls like you across the universe
她们有危险
who are in danger.
你可以留下 跟我们一起帮助她们
You can stay with us and help them.
我杀了灭霸就能帮助她们
I will help them by killing Thanos.
我不知道那是否能做到
I don't know if that's possible.
你永远是我妹妹
You will always be my sister.
彼得
Pete!
船长在一家旧货店为你找到了这个
Captain found this for you in a junker shop.
说你有一天会回来的
Said you'd come back to the fold someday.
是什么
What is it?
叫Zune
It's called a Zune.
地球人现在都听这玩意了
It's what everybody's listening to on Earth nowadays.
里面能存三百首歌
It's got 300 songs on it.
三百首歌
300 songs?
等等
Wait.
火箭把残片捡走 重拼了起来
Rocket grabbed the pieces, and reassembled them.
我觉得勇度会希望留给你的
I think Yondu would want you to have it.
谢谢
Thanks...
船长
Captain.
他们来了
They came.
是什么
What is it?
我给勇度以前的掠夺者朋友去了消息
I sent word to Yondu's old Ravager buddies,
把他做的事告诉了他们
and told them what he did.
这是掠夺者的葬礼
It's a Ravager funeral.
好啊
Yeah!
好
他终究没有辜负我们 船长
He didn't let us down after all, Captain.
是啊 孩子
No, he did not, son.
他没有
He did not.
永别了 老朋友
Fare thee well, old friend.
勇度·尤冬塔 我们在群星中再会
Yondu Udonta, I will see you in the stars.
他没把他们赶走
He didn't chase them away.
是啊
No.
虽然他吼他们
Even though he yelled at them.
总那么尖酸
And was always mean.
还偷了他用不着的电池
And he stole batteries he didn't need.
当然不会了
Well, of course not.
怎么了
What?
就是
It's just...
心照不宣的情愫
some unspoken thing.
真美
It's beautiful.
是啊
It is.
你也很美
And so are you.
内在美
On the inside.
银河护卫队
还将回归
真是遗憾
You know, it's a shame...
要失去勇度这样的惨剧
that it took the tragedy of losing Yondu
才让我们重聚
to bring us all together again.
但我觉得如果他知道我们重新组队
But I think he'd be proud knowing that
一定会骄傲的
we are back as a team.
我加入
I'm in.
太好了
Dope.
我想死你们了
I miss you guys so much!
太好了
Hell, yes.
我们去偷点东西吧
What say we steal some shit?
大祭司 理事会在等您
High Priestess, the Council is waiting.
他们不满我浪费了资源
They are perturbed I've wasted our resources.
等他们看到了我的创造
When they see what I have created here
他们的愤怒就会消散
their wrath will dissipate.
是新型生育荚吗 夫人
It's a new type of birthing pod, ma'am?
好孩子 那个
That, my child
是我们进化的下一步
is the next step in our evolution.
更强大 更美丽
More powerful, more beautiful,
更有能力摧毁银河护卫队
more capable of destroying the Guardians of the Galaxy.
我就叫他
I think I shall call him...
亚当吧
Adam.
哥们
Dude.
不是吧
Seriously?
你得清理你的房间 简直乱成一团
You gotta clean up your room. It's a complete mess.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
我才不无聊 你才无聊
I am not boring. You're boring.
你知道什么无聊吗
You know what's boring?
坐在那里 玩那个没劲的游戏
Sitting there, playing that mind-numbing game.
无聊的是我每天要被你的藤蔓绊倒
What's boring is me tripping over your vines every day!
我才不无聊
I'm not boring!
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
现在我能体会勇度当年的心情了
And now I know how Yondu felt.
在这艰难时期
In these times of hardship...
记住
just remember...
我们是格鲁特
We. Are. Groot.
伙计们
Hey, fellas.
等等 你们去哪
Wait, where are you going?
你们不是要送我回家的吗
You were supposed to be my lift home.
我要怎么离开啊
How will I get out of here?
天呐
Aw, gee...
我还有好多故事要讲呢
I've got so many more stories to tell.
伙计们
Aw, guys.
天呐
Oh, gee...